A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Public Affairs, News Clippings FA1439
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Public Affairs, News Clippings
1901-1969
1925-1960 (Bulk)
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
FA1439
5.18 Cubic Feet 6 legal-size document boxes, 1 letter-size document box, 2 half-legal document boxes, and 1 package.
Arrangement
Primarily chronological.
Biographical / Historical
In 1950 Eugene Harold Kone was appointed Public Relations Consultant of Rockefeller University. In his office various news releases were prepared and arrangements made for press coverage of certain events. News service clippings passed through this office and were sent for informational purposes to other offices in the University.
In October 1972 the post of Public Affairs Officer at the Rockefeller University was created to which Eric Manterfield was appointed. Eugene Kone continued as consultant working with communications media in collaboration with Eric Manterfield as the University's Public Information Associate.
The responsibility of the Public Affairs Officer will be for "developing programs to increase understanding of the University's research and educational activities by the local, national and international public it serves."
On June 7, 1974 Dr. Frederick Seitz announced the appointment of William J. Comcowich to the post of Public Affairs Officer.
Scope and Contents
Newspapers clippings, 1901-1960s. The majority of the material was originally housed in 4 bound scrapbooks comrpising the years: 1901-1924; 1925-1934; 1935-1941; and 1942-1960.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 365
- News Clippings - Rockefeller Gifts, c. 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- News Clippings - Rockefeller Institute Milk Dairies Investigation, c. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- News Clippings - Rockefeller Institute - Site to Promote Pathology and Hygiene, c. 1903 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- News Clippings - Opening Rockefeller Laboratories of Medical Research, c. 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- News Clippings - Rockefeller Institute - Vivisection and Campaign on Disease, c. 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- News Clippings - Vivisection War, Animal Lovers and Methods of Physiological Research, c. 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- News Clippings - Rockefeller Gifts and Institute Research-Infant Paralysis, Vivisection, Serum no. 606, Meningitis and Cancer findings, c. 1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- News Clippings - Rockefeller Hospital, Meningitis serum, Spotted Fever, Infant Paralysis, Tuberculosis, Organ Growth and Gender, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- News Clippings - New Anesthetic and Resuscitation Methods, Infant Paralysis, Pneumonia, Pasteurization, Cancer, Anti-Research, Hygiene and Modern Surgery, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- News Clippings - Reserve Bank, Rockefeller Millions for Starving War Sufferers, and War in Colorado, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- News Clippings - Land Deal on Carnegie Lake Starts Rumor, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- News Clippings - The National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild, and Gangrene Germs Conquered, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- News Clippings, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- News Clippings, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original articles are restricted due to preservation concerns.
- News Clippings - Polio, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
- News Clippings - Polio (Box 2, Folder 10-18)
- News Clippings - World War I (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
- News Clippings - World War I (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
- News Clippings, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- News Clippings - Ivy L. Lee Service, c. 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
- News Clippings, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- News Clippings - Insulin Fund, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- News Clippings - Insulin Fund and Ivy L. Lee Service, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
- News Clippings, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- News Clippings, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- News Clippings - Index, 1925 January-1934 June (Box 4, Folder 1)
- News Clippings - 1-100, 1925 January-1928 November (Box 4, Folder 2-51)
- News Clippings - 101-180, 1926 May-1930 December (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
- News Clippings - Landsteiner - Nobel Prize, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
- News Clippings - 181-200, 1930 December-1931 December (Box 5, Folder 14-17)
- News Clippings - 101-200, 1926 May-1931 December (Box 5, Folder 18-29)
  Restricted - Original articles are restricted due to preservation concerns.
- News Clippings - 201-240, 1931 May-1934 June (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- News Clippings - 201-240, 1931 May-1934 June (Box 6, Folder 19-23)
  Restricted - Original material is restricted due to preservation concerns.
- News Clippings - Index, 1934 September-1941 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- News Clippings - 241-6, 1934 June-1935 July (Box 6, Folder 7)
- News Clippings - 241-6, 1934 June-1935 July (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Restricted - Original archival material is restricted due to preservation concerns.
- News Clippings - 7-90, 1935 March-1937 April (Box 6, Folder 8-18)
- News Clippings - 7-90, 1935 March-1937 April (Box 6, Folder 25-35)
- News Clippings - 91-208, 1937 January-1941 December (Box 7, Folder 1-15)
- News Clippings - 91-208, 1937 January-1941 December (Box 7, Folder 16-30)
- News Clippings - 209-240, 1941 January-December (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
- News Clippings - 209-240, 1941 January-December (Box 8, Folder 16-20)
- News Clippings - 1-78, 1942 January-1947 September (Box 8, Folder 5-14)
- News Clippings - 1-78, 1942 January-1947 September (Box 8, Folder 20-29)
- News Clippings - Index, 1942-1960 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- News Clippings - 79-188, 1947 July-1960 April (Box 9, Folder 1-14)
- News Clippings - 79-188, 1947 July-1960 April (Box 9, Folder 17-30)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1910-1940s (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1910-1940s (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1950-1960s (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1950-1960s (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Public Relations Office - Press Book, 1957-1959 (Box 10)
- Ivy L. Lee, 1919, 1920 (Box 13)